# **Swetabh Suman**

LinkedIn: /in/swetabhsuman

Location: Bengaluru, Karnataka, India Email: swtbhsmn@gmail.com | Mobile: +91 7903385534

### **SUMMARY**

Experienced in Software **Front-end** and **Back-end** development with 2+ years of experience. I believe, I am a good learner and describe myself as a lifelong learner and implementer. I prefer smart work but always ready for hard work if required.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **Software Engineer**

Janurary 2022 – Present

DataGrokr Analytics Pvt. Ltd.

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

- Led the successful migration of a monolithic architecture to a micro-services based architecture, significantly
  improving scalability, flexibility, and performance.
- As a **full-stack developer**, I worked on multiple projects. Responsibilities include designing, developing and optimizing features, troubleshooting production issues, and handle releases.

## **Software Engineer Intern**

July 2021 – December 2021

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

Datagrokr Analytics Pvt. Ltd.

- Implemented responsive design principles to ensure seamless user experiences across devices and platforms.
- Worked with a team to implement RESTful APIs in Express.js, enabling analytics teams to increase reporting speed.

## **SKILLS**

**Languages** : Python, JavaScript, TypeScript, SQL

Technologies and Tools

: ReactJS, NodeJS, Redux, Angular, Amazon Web Services (AWS), Flask, Chalice, Docker, CI/CD, Okta, Splunk, Swagger, REST API, TDD, Jira, Git, MySQL, HTML, CSS, JSON, Shell Scripting

## **EDUCATION**

# **Lovely Professional University**

Phagwara, Punjab, India

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science And Engineering

July 2017 – June 2021

#### **PROJECTS**

# **Real-Time Collaborative Text Editor**

React, Sanic (Python framework), WebSocket, Git etc

• Developed a real-time text editor using React for the front end and Sanic, a Python framework, for the backend. This project enables multiple users to collaborate on the same document.

**Resource Management Portal**React, Lambda, Apigateway, DynamoDB, Echarts, S3, Okta, CloudFront, Git etc.

• The Resource Management Portal aims to provide a comprehensive platform for managing and tracking resources within an organization

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Coursera: Server-side Development with NodeJS, Express and MongoDB HTR2B8SRGNM7
- Amazon Web Services: AWS Certified Developer(Associate) RG1WN5MCVMEEQ7K9

## **HOBBIES**

- · Learning new technology
- · DIY projects
- Traveling